<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="content.conflicts">
    <title>Conflict Notifications</title>

    <para>
        If you are editing a content entry and someone else saves a change to the same entry, or
        deletes the entry, a <emphasis>conflict</emphasis> could occur. If you then save your
        changes, you could be undoing important changes made by the other user. &product.longname;
        provides basic conflict notification when these situations occur.
    </para>

    <para>
        If you begin editing a content entry that another user is already editing, a
        <emphasis role="dialog">Conflict</emphasis> dialog appears:
    </para>

    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-edit-conflict.png"/>
        </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>
        &product.name; checks periodically to see if any changes have been made to the content entry
        you are editing. If a change has been made, a notification appears informing you which user
        made the change:
    </para>

    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/notification-other_user_edit.png"/>
        </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>
        If you click the link, a <emphasis role="dialog">Diff</emphasis> dialog appears so you can
        see what changes were made. Please refer to <xref linkend="content.history.view.diff"/> for
        more details.
    </para>

    <para>
        Sometimes the interval between changes being saved amongst users is so small that you may
        not see the conflict notification. When this occurs, a <emphasis role="dialog">Save
        Conflict</emphasis> dialog appears.
    </para>

    <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-save_conflict.png"/>
        </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>

    <para>
        The dialog reports which user made the change, and also allows you to see what changes were
        made. You can click <guibutton>Overwrite</guibutton> to replace the other user's changes
        with your own, or <guibutton>Cancel</guibutton> to continue editing.
    </para>

    <para>
        How you deal with such conflicts is up to you. You may wish to:

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                overwrite the other user's changes
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                cancel your own changes
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                reproduce the same changes the other user made and then overwrite.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <para>
        Since &product.name; keeps track of every change, even if you overwrite another user's
        changes, they are not lost.
    </para>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->