<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="content.type.overview">
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>
        A <emphasis>content type</emphasis> provides structure to your content. A simple content
        entry might have a <emphasis>title</emphasis> and a <emphasis>body</emphasis>. Instead of
        relying on visual styles or layout to distinguish where the title ends and the
        body begins, content types use <emphasis>elements</emphasis> to identify the title and
        body as individual components of content. Such structure helps ensure that your content is
        composed and displayed consistently.
    </para>

    <para>
        &product.longname; provides a set of basic content types for adding pages, files, images and
        so on. You can create or modify content types to fit your content's requirements from the
        simple to the complex. Also provided is a library of elements to help you compose new
        content types. These include text, date, editor, imageFile. Custom modules can provide
        additional elements. Each element you use in content can be configured with a label and
        optional features such as:
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <emphasis>Filters</emphasis>: these can modify user-supplied information to remove
            undesirable content. For example, a filter could remove surrounding whitespace, remove
            <acronym>HTML</acronym> tags, or convert special characters into <acronym>HTML</acronym>
            entities.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            <emphasis>Validators</emphasis>: these help users to enter information in the format
            you expect. For example, a phone number element might restrict users to entering
            numbers, periods, and dashes, where the numbers must be in two groups of three followed
            by a group of four.
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>
        Theme designers can create <emphasis>view scripts</emphasis>, which specify how a specific
        content type is to be displayed. Please see <xref linkend="themes.view.scripts"/> for more
        details.
    </para>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->