<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="userguide.overview">
    <title>Overview of &product.longname; Web Site Editing</title>

    <para>
        &product.name; is a web content management system that enables you to manage your web
        content in a simple, easy, and efficient manner. You can make quick edits to your content or
        dig into the raw <acronym>HTML</acronym> and make more in-depth changes. This chapter
        covers the basics of creating and managing web content, and reviewing the history of your
        content as it changes over time.
    </para>

    <section id="content.edit.features">
        <title>Notable Editing Features</title>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">In-Place Mode and Form Mode</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    In-Place Mode allows editing content within the page layout, with the position
                    and appearance maintained. This makes it significantly easier to make changes
                    to suit the presentation.
                </para>

                <para>
                    Form Mode provides more traditional editing of content where each element in the
                    content, including those hidden from normal presentation, is displayed in a
                    form.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Change Notifications</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    While you are editing a content entry, if another user edits or deletes the same
                    content entry, a notification appears so you can decide how to proceed.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Style Controls</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    The &product.name; editor provides commonplace style controls, such as typeface
                    selection, type size, tag selection, color, alignment, indentation, bullets,
                    link creation, and image inclusion. There is a "source" mode when custom markup
                    is required.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Content Types</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    Content types allow you to define the structure of your content. A content entry
                    might be as simple as a <emphasis>title</emphasis> and a
                    <emphasis>body</emphasis>, or require many more elements such as
                    <emphasis>dates</emphasis>, <emphasis>images</emphasis>,
                    <emphasis>selections</emphasis>.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Menus &amp; Categories</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    &product.name; provides menus and categories which provide the tools so you can
                    organize your content both for logical and navigational purposes.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Workflows</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    Workflows are processes you can create and use to help guide your content from
                    creation to publication. A simple workflow might include the states
                    <emphasis>draft</emphasis> and <emphasis>published</emphasis>, but content for
                    more technically-oriented audiences may require review states such as
                    <emphasis>technical</emphasis>, <emphasis>language</emphasis>,
                    <emphasis>legal</emphasis>, and <emphasis>marketing</emphasis>. Workflows can
                    restrict <emphasis>transitions</emphasis> between states by
                    <emphasis>conditions</emphasis>, such as which user is making changes.
                    Successful transitions can invoke <emphasis>actions</emphasis>, such as
                    notifying reviewers when transitions occur.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Widgets</emphasis>
                </para>

                <para>
                    Widgets allow you to customize the appearance of pages with features such as
                    additional text, images, menus and more without requiring any knowledge of
                    <acronym>HTML</acronym>. You might use widgets to provide contact information
                    throughout your site, or to highlight new product images.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->
