<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="social.sharethis">
    <title>ShareThis</title>

    <para>
        The optional ShareThis module helps your site's users share your content through popular
        social media services like Facebook, Twitter, Google+. It uses ShareThis service
        (<ulink url="http://www.sharethis.com/">www.sharethis.com</ulink>), which provides buttons
        for selected social media services (over 100 to choose from); each button provides an
        interface to facilitate easy content sharing.
    </para>

    <para>
        Features include:
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            Supports up to
            <ulink url="http://sharethis.com/publishers/services-directory">100 social media
            services</ulink>.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Configurable button styles.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Default button inclusion configurable by content type.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Detailed page analytics are available at sharethis.com via your publisher key.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            You can decide where to provide sharing buttons per content entry.
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section>
        <title>Configuring the ShareThis Module</title>

        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                Ensure that the ShareThis module is enabled. Please refer to
                <xref linkend="modules.management.enable-disable"/>.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Choose <command>Manage > Modules</command>. The <emphasis role="screen">Manage
                Modules</emphasis> screen is displayed, listing available modules.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Scroll down to ShareThis.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Click <guibutton>Configure</guibutton>. A dialog appears presenting the ShareThis
                module configuration:

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-sharethis_configuration.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Select the desired button presentation in the <emphasis role="bold">Button
                Style</emphasis> field. <emphasis>Large</emphasis> and <emphasis>Small</emphasis>
                refer to the button sizes. <emphasis>Vertical Counters</emphasis> and
                <emphasis>Horizontal Counters</emphasis> provides large buttons along with a
                <emphasis>counter</emphasis> displaying the number of clicks received.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Select the services/buttons to be displayed below your content entries. The
                    <emphasis>Selected Services</emphasis> box on the left contains services whose
                    buttons (in the given order) are to be displayed with your content. The list of
                    selected services defaults to ShareThis, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Email.
                    The <emphasis>Available Services</emphasis> box on the right contains all
                    available sharing services. Note: the selected services can be changed at any
                    time, and the selected services apply for all content entries.
                </para>

                <para>
                    To change the order of your Selected Services, drag-and-drop the service to the
                    desired position. Services can be removed by dragging them from the
                    <emphasis>Selected Services</emphasis> box to the <emphasis>Available
                    Services</emphasis> box. Services can be added by dragging them from the
                    <emphasis>Available Services</emphasis> box to the <emphasis>Selected
                    Services</emphasis> box.
                </para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Select which content types should present ShareThis buttons by default.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Optionally enter a publisher key. A publisher key can be obtained by signing up
                for a <emphasis>Publisher Account</emphasis> at
                <ulink url="http://www.sharethis.com/register">sharethis.com</ulink>. You can also
                generate a random key by clicking on the 'Generate Key' button. However, to access
                the ShareThis analytics, this publisher key must be registered with your
                www.sharethis.com account by contacting their support service.
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Adding ShareThis Buttons to Content</title>

        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                Navigate to the content entry for which you wish to add ShareThis buttons.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Click <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> in the &product.name; toolbar to begin
                editing.

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/toolbar-content-edit.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Click the <guibutton>ShareThis</guibutton> button in the toolbar.

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/toolbar-edit_content-sharethis-focus.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>

                <para></para>

                The ShareThis dialog appears:

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-content_edit-sharethis.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Make the <emphasis>Show ShareThis Buttons</emphasis> checkbox checked.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Click <guibutton>Save</guibutton> to save the ShareThis configuration. The social
                services selected in the ShareThis module configuration appears below the content
                entry.
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <note>
        <title>Problems with ShareThis?</title>

        <para>
            Chronicle's ShareThis module integrates the ShareThis service with Chronicle. The
            presentation of service sharing buttons, and all functionality they provide, is
            controlled by the ShareThis service. If you encounter any problems, please consult with
            ShareThis <ulink url="http://support.sharethis.com/">technical support</ulink>.
        </para>
    </note>

    <note>
        <title>Using the Tableau theme?</title>

        <para>
            Please review <link linkend="tableau.social">the adjustments to Disqus
            conversations</link> when the Tableau theme is active.
        </para>
    </note>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->