<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="widgets.configure">
    <title>Configuring Widgets</title>

    <bridgehead>
        To configure a widget:
    </bridgehead>

    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            Click <guibutton>Widgets</guibutton> in the &product.longname; toolbar.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/toolbar-manage-widgets.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            &product.name; displays highlighted regions indicating existing widgets that can be
            configured.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/widget-detail-configure.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Click the configure icon for the widget you wish to configure. The
            <emphasis role="dialog">Configure Widget</emphasis> dialog appears.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-configure_widget.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Adjust the configuration for the widget. Please see
            <xref linkend="widgets.configure.options"/> for more details.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Click <guibutton>Save</guibutton> to finish adding the new widget.
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <section id="widgets.configure.options">
        <title>Widget Configuration Options</title>

        <para>
            All widgets have a set of general options that enable you to configure them as follows:
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Title</term>

                <listitem>
                    The title for this widget.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show Title</term>

                <listitem>
                    Toggles the display of the widget's title in the region.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Order</term>

                <listitem>
                    Influences the order of the widget in the region; higher numbers cause
                    widgets to be displayed later in the region, lower or negative numbers
                    cause widgets to be displayed earlier in the region.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>CSS Class</term>

                <listitem>
                    Enter a <acronym>CSS</acronym> class name to distinguish this widget
                    from other widgets of the same type, to provide custom styling. You
                    may need access to the current theme's stylesheet file to make full
                    use of this feature.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Load Asynchronously</term>

                <listitem>
                    Skips execution of the widget on the initial page view and loads its display
                    via a separate request using <acronym>AJAX</acronym>. This is ideal for
                    widgets that take a noticeable amount of time to run and that might slow down
                    page loading, for example any widget that calls an external service such as
                    Twitter.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>
            Each type of widget has its own custom options. The following sections detail the custom
            options provided by the built in widgets.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.associatedcategories">
        <title>Associated Categories Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget lists any categories that have been assigned to the content being
            displayed.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Preamble</term>

                <listitem>
                    (optional) Text to be displayed before the category list.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.contentlistwidget">
        <title>Content List Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget displays a list of content entries, and provides an RSS feed of the listing.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Maximum Items</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies the maximum number of content entries to be displayed.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show Icons</term>

                <listitem>
                    When checked, icons indicating each content entry's content type is included in
                    the listing.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Content Types</term>

                <listitem>
                    Select the content type(s) to include in the listing.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Primary Sort</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify which field within the content entries should be used to sort the
                    listing, and the sort direction.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Secondary Sort</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify which field within the content entries should be used to sort the
                    listing when the Primary Sort encounters identical values, and the sort
                    direction.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show RSS Link</term>

                <listitem>
                    When checked, a link to the listing's feed is included in the top-right of
                    the listing. Note that the feed for the widget is available whether the link
                    is included or not.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Feed Title (only visible when Show RSS Link is checked)</term>

                <listitem>
                    (optional) Specify the title of the RSS feed. When empty, the widget's Title
                    value is used as the feed's title.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Feed Description (only visible when Show RSS Link is checked)</term>

                <listitem>
                    (optional) Specify the description of the RSS feed. When empty, the widget's
                    Title value is used as the feed's description.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.feedwidget">
        <title>Feed Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget displays an RSS or Atom feed. The Feed module is optional and must be
            enabled to make the Feed widget available. Please refer to
            <xref linkend="modules.management.enable-disable"/>.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Feed <acronym>URL</acronym></term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies the <acronym>URL</acronym> of the feed source. Both RSS and Atom feeds
                    are supported, and are automatically recognized.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show Source <acronym>URL</acronym></term>

                <listitem>
                    When checked, an extra line displaying the feed source <acronym>URL</acronym>
                    is included in the feed presentation.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show Dates</term>

                <listitem>
                    When checked, each feed item includes its publication date.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Show Descriptions</term>

                <listitem>
                    When checked, each feed item includes its description (when available).
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Maximum Items</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies the maximum number of feed items to be displayed.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.image">
        <title>Image Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget displays an image.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Local image file / Remote image address</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify if we are selecting an image content entry or providing a
                    <acronym>URL</acronym>.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Image File</term>

                <listitem>
                    If using local image file, this field is used to select the image.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Image Address</term>

                <listitem>
                    If using remote image file, this field is used to specify the
                    <acronym>URL</acronym>.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Alt Text</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify the Alternate Text to be used if images are not shown.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify a width that the browser should scale the image to.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify a height that the browser should scale the image to.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Link</term>

                <listitem>
                    Provide a <acronym>URL</acronym> which should be visited when the image is
                    clicked.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Link Target</term>

                <listitem>
                    If using a link, specifies which window to open in.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <note>
            <title>Server-Side Image Resizing</title>

            <para>
                If the web server hosting &product.name; has a supported <acronym>PHP</acronym>
                image library installed (see <xref linkend="chapter.image.manipulation"/> for
                more details), local images with a specified width/height are resized on the
                server to minimize data transfer and improve page load time.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.image-rotator">
        <title>Image Rotator Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget displays a sequence of images, with cross-fading. Depending on browser
            capabilities, scaling, panning, and cross-fading effects may also be applied for a more
            interesting presentation.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Images</term>

                <listitem>
                    Displays the list of images to be rotated. The <guibutton>Browse</guibutton>
                    button beside each entry allows you to choose the image for that position in
                    the list. The <guibutton>Clear</guibutton> button removes the image from that
                    position in the list. Use the <emphasis>Caption</emphasis> field to enter
                    descriptive text that displays at the bottom of the image. Use the
                    <emphasis>Link</emphasis> field to specify a <acronym>URL</acronym> to visit
                    when the image is clicked.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Width</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify a width for the widget to rotate images within.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Height</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specify a height for the widget to rotate images within.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <note>
            <title>Default Size</title>

            <para>
                Unless specified, images displayed by the rotator occupy the full width of the
                widget. Normally, only the height needs to be provided to achieve the desired
                presentation.
            </para>
        </note>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.menuwidget">
        <title>Menu Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget displays a menu of links to categories, content items, or the
            &product.longname; toolbar.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Menu</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies the name of the menu to display.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Display Root</term>

                <listitem>
                    Limits display to only entries contained under a given path.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Include Content</term>

                <listitem>
                    When using the categories menu, specifies whether links to the associated
                    content entries are listed below each category's link.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Maximum Depth</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies how many levels of subitems (indentation) are displayed.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry>
                <term>Maximum Items</term>

                <listitem>
                    Specifies the maximum number of menu items to be displayed.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.search">
        <title>Search Widgets</title>

        <para>
            The search widget provides a method of looking for content entries based on
            keyword(s). It provides no custom configuration options. To specify advanced
            searches, use
            <ulink url="http://framework.zend.com/manual/en/zend.search.lucene.query-language.html">
            Lucene Query Language</ulink>.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="widgets.configure.text">
        <title>Text Widget</title>

        <para>
            This widget provides a <acronym>WYSIWYG</acronym> interface to display arbitrary
            text.
        </para>

        <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
                <term>Text</term>

                <listitem>
                    (optional) <acronym>HTML</acronym> formatted text to be displayed.
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
    </section>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->