<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="widgets.overview">
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>
        <emphasis>Widgets</emphasis> are like mini-applications that you can embed in Web pages.
        &product.longname; comes with a set of default widgets, and you can add your own widgets to
        this set. Widgets are displayed in a dedicated <emphasis>region</emphasis> specified by the
        current theme, and you can configure the order (top to bottom) in which they are displayed.
    </para>

    <para>
        Widgets are provided by modules. To add or remove widgets from &product.name; you need to
        have appropriate privileges in the application as well as access to the filesystem where
        modules are stored. Please see <xref linkend="modules.management.addremove"/> for more
        details.
    </para>

    <para>
        &product.name; ships with the following widgets:
    </para>

    <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Associated Categories</term>

            <listitem>
                The Associated Categories widget is designed to display any categories associated
                with the currently displayed content entry. Each displayed category is linked so
                that users can discover additional content in each category.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
            <term>Image Widget</term>

            <listitem>
                The Image Widget allows you to display an image; either one that has already been
                added to &product.name;, or from a remote web site.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
            <term>Menu Widget</term>

            <listitem>
                The Menu Widget allows you to display a menu, or a subset of a menu. You can choose
                the menu, the starting point within its hierarchy, limit the depth of entries to
                be displayed, and limit the total number of entries.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
            <term>Recent Content</term>

            <listitem>
                The Recent Content widget lists the most recently created or modified content
                entries, up to a limit you specify.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
            <term>Search Widget</term>

            <listitem>
                The Search Widget provides a search interface so that users can locate content
                entries based on the text they contain.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>

        <varlistentry>
            <term>Text Widget</term>

            <listitem>
                The Text Widget allows you to place arbitrary text on a page.
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->