<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="workflows.scheduled.transitions">
    <title>Scheduling Transitions</title>

    <para>
        When a content entry is saved, if you have sufficient privileges to change the workflow
        state, you are given the option to have the workflow change immediately or at a
        future date. This feature is useful if you prefer to prepare content for publication
        early and wish to avoid having to manually publish content at the appropriate time.
    </para>

    <bridgehead>
        To transition content in the future:
    </bridgehead>

    <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
            Begin adding or editing a content entry. Please see <xref linkend="content.add"/>, or
            <xref linkend="content.edit"/> for more details.
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Click the <guibutton>Save</guibutton> button.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/toolbar-edit_content-save.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>

            The <emphasis role="dialog">Save Content</emphasis> dialog is displayed:

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-save_content.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Select a workflow state to which the content should transition. For these steps,
            <emphasis>Publish</emphasis> is selected.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-save_content-focus_publish.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>

            The dialog expands to display the scheduling options.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-save_content-schedule.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Click <emphasis role="bold">Now</emphasis> to indicate that the workflow transition
            should occur immediately. Or click <emphasis role="bold">Specify Server Date and
            Time</emphasis>, then use the controls just below to select a date and time.

            <note>
                <title>Server Time Display</title>

                <para>
                    The current web server time is displayed to help you decide on a date and time
                    for a state transition.
                </para>
            </note>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
            Click the <guibutton>Save</guibutton> button to save your content.

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-save_content-focus_save.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <note>
        <title>Content Edits Saved Immediately</title>

        <para>
            Whether you choose to transition your content to a new state immediately or sometime
            in the future, when you click <guibutton>Save</guibutton> any additions or modifications
            to your content entry are saved immediately.
        </para>
    </note>

    <section id="workflows.scheduled.transitions.batch">
        <title>Scheduling Workflow Transitions for Multiple Entries</title>

        <para>
            You can also schedule workflow transitions for multiple entries at once by selecting entries
            via the <emphasis role="screen">Manage Content</emphasis> screen.
        </para>

        <note>
            <title>Please be patient</title>

            <para>
                Scheduling a large number of workflow transitions can take some time.
            </para>
        </note>

        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                Click <guibutton>Content</guibutton> in the &product.longname; toolbar.

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/toolbar-manage-content_focus.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>

                The <emphasis role="screen">Manage Content</emphasis> screen is displayed.

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/screen-manage_content.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Select the entries you want to schedule a workflow transition for:

                <note>
                    <title>Do Not Click the Entry's Title</title>

                    <para>
                        When selecting one or more entries, click on the entry's row, but not the
                        entry's title.
                    </para>
                </note>

                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        To select a single entry, click on the entry's row.
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                        To add entry into the selection, use <keycombo><keycap>CTRL</keycap>
                        <mousebutton>Left-click</mousebutton></keycombo>
                        (<keycombo><keycap>Command</keycap><mousebutton>Left-click</mousebutton>
                        </keycombo> on Mac) on the desired entry's row.
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                        To remove entry from the selection, use <keycombo><keycap>CTRL</keycap>
                        <mousebutton>Left-click</mousebutton></keycombo>
                        (<keycombo><keycap>Command</keycap><mousebutton>Left-click</mousebutton>
                        </keycombo> on Mac) on the not-desired entry's row.
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                        You can also select a range of entries by selecting the first entry in the range
                        and then holding a <keycap>Shift</keycap> key and clicking on the row of the
                        last entry.
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>

                The number of selected entries is shown in the grid footer beside the indicator of the
                total number of entries.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Click the <guibutton>Workflow</guibutton> button in the grid footer; this button
                is activated when one or more entries are selected. The
                <emphasis role="dialog">Change Workflow Status</emphasis> dialog is displayed.

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-change_workflow_status.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>

                Here you can specify which workflow state the selected content entries should
                transition to, when the transition should occur, and an optional comment to
                describe the transition.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Select a workflow state to which the selected content entries should transition.
                </para>

                <para>
                    The list of workflow states is composed of the intersection of matching states from
                    the workflows of all selected entries. For example, if there are two distinct
                    workflows for all selected entries, where the first workflow defines
                    <emphasis>draft</emphasis>, <emphasis>review</emphasis> and
                    <emphasis>published</emphasis> states, and the second workflow defines
                    <emphasis>draft</emphasis>, <emphasis>published</emphasis>
                    and <emphasis>obsolete</emphasis>, the list of states contains only the options
                    <emphasis>draft</emphasis> and <emphasis>published</emphasis>. 
                    The <emphasis>review</emphasis> and <emphasis>obsolete</emphasis> states are not
                    included because they do not exist in both workflows.
                </para>

                <para>
                    Workflow states from multiple workflows may have differing labels. When this occurs,
                    the labels for a common state are all displayed, separated by slashes.
                </para>

                Finally, the list of workflow states does not represent content entries that have no
                associated workflow.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                Select a scheduling option for the status changes.
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Click the <guibutton>Change Status</guibutton> button. &product.name; prepares the
                    transition for all selected content entries.
                </para>

                <para>
                    When successful, a notification appears indicating the number of entries processed.
                </para>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/notification-changed_workflow_status-success.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>

                <para>
                    Upon failure to prepare the transition for one or more entries, a warning dialog is
                    displayed where you can see how many entries cannot be transited to the selected
                    workflow state:
                </para>

                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/dialog-change_workflow_status-failure.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>

                <para>
                    At this point, no changes to the selected entries have been made. Click on the
                    <guibutton>Continue</guibutton> button if you wish to schedule workflow transition
                    for only those entries where it is allowed.
                </para>


                <para>
                    There are several reasons, why scheduling a workflow transition may be denied on
                    some entries:
                </para>

                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        One or more of the selected entries is/are not under any workflow and the
                        selected workflow status is not <emphasis>published</emphasis>.
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                        Selected workflow transition is not allowed on one or more of the selected
                        entries due to one or more
                        <link linkend="workflows.configure.conditions">conditions</link> attached to the
                        transition.
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                        You don't have a permission to edit one or more of the selected entries.
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>

                <warning>
                    <para>
                        Please be aware that what you see in the workflow status selection list are
                        workflow state labels (friendlier identifiers) that are
                        <emphasis role="bold">not</emphasis> used as identifiers of workflow states
                        when workflow transition options are calculated.
                    </para>
                </warning>

            </listitem>

        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="workflow.scheduled.transitions.grid">
        <title>Reviewing Scheduled Workflow Transitions</title>

        <para>
            When viewing the content grid, any entries with pending workflow state transitions
            are indicated in the Workflow column. If you hover your mouse over the transition
            indicator, a tooltip appears providing details of the transition:

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/tooltip-workflow_schedule.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
    </section>

    <note>
        <title>Processing Scheduled Workflow Transitions</title>

        <para>
            Scheduled workflow transitions are processed automatically by the
            <classname>Cron</classname> module, but depend on sufficiently regular activation to
            meet your scheduling expectations. Please see <xref linkend="site.time-based-tasks"/>
            for more details.
        </para>
    </note>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->
