<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="users.overview">
    <title>Overview</title>

    <para>
        This chapter covers the management aspects of users, roles, and permissions.
    </para>

    <para>
        A <emphasis>user</emphasis> in &product.longname; means a user account registered with the
        underlying Perforce server that stores all your site's content. User accounts allow
        people to login to your site to provide content or perform other actions.
    </para>

    <para>
        The actions users may perform are dictated by the <emphasis>roles</emphasis> assigned to
        them. By default, each created user account is assigned the <emphasis>member</emphasis>
        role, which permits the user to access and create content. Assigning additional roles
        to a user adds to the actions the user may perform.
    </para>

    <para>
        Permissions describe the <emphasis>privileges</emphasis>, which are provided by
        <emphasis>resources</emphasis> such as modules, that each role can bestow upon a user.
    </para>

    <note>
        <title>What Happens When a User is Deleted?</title>

        <para>
            When a user account is deleted, the user account registered with the underlying Perforce
            server is removed, along with any roles assigned to the user. None of the content entries
            created or owned by the user, nor any other records, are removed or changed in any way.
        </para>

        <para>
            If a user is subsequently created with the same userid, and is assigned the same roles,
            the user regains access to all previously created content with that userid.
        </para>
    </note>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->