<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section
[
    <!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../../en/xinclude.mod">
    %xinclude;

    <!-- Add translated specific definitions and snippets -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets SYSTEM "../standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets;

    <!-- Fallback to English definitions and snippets (in case of missing translation) -->
    <!ENTITY % language-snippets.default SYSTEM "../../en/standalone/language-snippets.xml">
    %language-snippets.default;
]>
<section id="introduction.welcome" role="sidebar">
    <title>Welcome!</title>

    <para>
        Welcome to the 2012.3 release of &product.longname;. This release features the result of our
        <emphasis>tablet-first</emphasis> initiative, a new theme called
        <emphasis>Tableau</emphasis> that uses magazine-like styling combined with gesture-based
        navigation and responsive layouts to resemble native apps for mobile devices.
    </para>

    <para>
        &product.name; supports a built-in staging and deployment workflow to quickly get the right
        content, to the right place, at the right time. Your web team will no longer have to rely on
        error-prone web publishing tools and time-consuming staging and deployment processes. Using
        Perforce's Enterprise Version Management technology as its foundation, only a click is
        required to create new staging and development environments with &product.longname;. With
        this built-in workflow, taking new content live has never been so simple regardless of the
        number of users or amount and type of content you are managing.
    </para>

    <para>
        &product.name; gives you the creativity you want and the control you need. It combines an
        easy-to-use <acronym>WYSIWYG</acronym> editor with enterprise-class version management. You
        can create your own themes and content types, and can extend the product by creating modules
        and widgets. &product.name; is highly customizable, and we have taken great care to ensure
        that web developers will be able to do amazing things with it.
    </para>

    <sidebar id="introduction.program.sidebar">
        <section label="Unsupported, Open Source Software">
            <subtitle>
                <inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject role="inline">
                        <imagedata width="62" fileref="images/icon-user.jpg" format="JPG"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject>
                Unsupported, Open Source Software
            </subtitle>

            <para>
                &product.name; is provided as open source software. No support will be provided to
                you for your use or modification of the code.
            </para>

            <mediaobject>
                <textobject>
                    <link linkend="introduction.opensource"><emphasis>See Our License</emphasis></link>
                </textobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </section>
    </sidebar>
</section>
<!--
vim:se ts=4 sw=4 et:
-->